My name is Ryan Wells.
I'm the owner of a local fish store in Lindon, Utah, called Reef Runners.
There are various ways to keep a tank clean.
First of all, let's briefly define what clean is.
A lot of people determine a clean tank by one that has little to no visible algae, the water is clear, and that your livestock is very healthy looking.
If you have algae problems, this can often be called a dirty tank.
In order to get rid of algae, there's some simple tips you can do, in cleaning your tank.
First of all, don't overstock your tank, and don't overfeed the livestock that you currently have in your tank.
Another important thing to keep in mind, is that you have current livestock in there, to help control your algae, or the overall cleanliness of your tank.
A lot of these include hermit crabs, different algae eating snails, some starfish, and even some of your fish may nip at, or eliminate different types of algae.
Once again, in order to keep your tank clean, the most important thing to do, is regular water changes, and keeping the cleanliness of your water overall.
If you have a buildup of nutrients, or different types of pollutants, this is what will cause a dirty or unclean tank.